# Michael J. Turley

208 Prospect St, Athol, MA 01331

781-264-6283 — mike@miketurley.com — github.com/mturley

**OVERVIEW** 

Michael is a pragmatic and creative software engineer with over 7 years of experience in web, mobile, and desktop application development, systems architecture, DevOps, QA, graphics, databases, IT and customer service. He currently works in central Massachusetts.

**EDUCATION** 

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science University of Massachusetts Amherst

Spring 2015 Amherst, MA

Dean's List Student - Member: UMass ACM, CS Recruiting and Outreach Committee

COMPUTER SKILLS

Scala, Java, C/C++, JavaScript, Python, Ruby, PHP, HTML5/CSS3 Languages Web Tools (Client) NPM, Webpack, Gulp, Bower, React, Angular, iQuery, Meteor Web Tools (Server) Nginx, Play Framework, Akka, Node.js, Rails, Wordpress, Meteor Databases MySQL/SQLite/Postgres, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Vertica, DynamoDB Infrastructure Tools Jenkins, Ansible, Chef, Amazon EC2/S3, DigitalOcean, Linode, Heroku GNU/Linux, Mac OS X, Windows, Android, iOS Operating Systems Design Software LATEX, Photoshop, Illustrator, AfterEffects, Premiere, Maya

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Hewlett Packard Enterprise

Spring 2015 - Present

Software Engineer, InfoSight / StoreFront Remote (HPE Storage Analytics) Andover, MA

- Built and maintained many advanced high-profile features for a highly available webapp
- Worked heavily at all levels of the stack using JavaScript, Scala, Play, Akka and more
- Collaborated with and learned from a small Scrum team of HP Engineers and Architects
- Contributed heavily to a major UI integration upon HPE's aquisition of Nimble Storage

## Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Summer 2014

Software Development Engineer Intern, AWS Storage Gateway team

Cambridge, MA

2011-2013

- Developed a new Amazon-internal website for Gateway support using Ruby on Rails
- Enhanced customer-facing diagnostic and logging tools using Java and Bash

## NimbleBot.com Interactive Software & Digital Design

Contract Web Application Developer in Javascript, PHP & MySQL Cambridge, MA

- $\bullet$  Designed and developed round-trip and real-time web apps and REST APIs
  - Took a leadership role on a team of 4 developers to build, debug, and deploy
  - Interfaced with clients and prepared deliverable reports

# Learn360.com K-12 Education Multimedia

Spring 2011

Software Tester & Frontend Prototype Developer

Woodbury, NY

• Tested for regressions and built patches for proposed improvements to the UI

#### Depot Street Market

2010-Present

Business Software Developer & Database Administrator

Duxbury, MA (Telecommute)

- Designed and developed PHP/MySQL apps for managing accounting data
- Built custom barcode label management and cash register & reporting software

#### ResNet Resource Center at Northeastern University

PC Repair Technician & Service Tool Developer

2008-2009 Boston, MA

• Collaborated with a team of technicians on service-related projects and tools

- Provided customer service and tech support for students & faculty

#### INTERESTS

Hobby programming projects, experimenting with new languages and platforms Music composition and performance on piano, bass, guitar, and voice Skiing, snowboarding, hiking, swimming, and running